What would the Gamilas want with this ancient battleship?
It's them!
Why would they attack something like this?
The enemy is presently bombing the Bonomisaki Cape area.
All personnel, remain on standby in the shelter.
Will we be okay?
We're boarding that ship. We can't die here!
Where are they coming from?
A carrier?
It's the Air Defense Forces.
This is Alpha Leader.
We've finished the welcoming party for our guests.
OK, Alpha Leader. We've confirmed it from here, as well.
Return to base immediately.
Roger.
Those idiots.
Hey, what's your problem? You're leaving us here?
It's alive...
This rusted old ship...
Pluto
<Shouldn't we report this to Commander Goer, on planet Balan?>
<We lost a carrier.>
<And what do you think will happen if that opportunist reports this to headquarters?>
<We'll deal with it ourselves.>
<We'll destroy it from long range. Ready the planet bombs.>
<Yes, sir!>
<We cannot fail.>
Okay, be careful with that hand.
Hey, he's glaring at us...
It's nice to be young. The radiation...
Well, I'm sure it'll be fine.
I won't be seeing you for a while, Mew.
Come to think of it, didn't you get the order to go, too?
Y-Yes, sir.
All over the world, energy sources are drying up.
To make matters worse, famine, riots, and poisonous spores
from those strange plants are destroying the planet.
We've very little time left...
Now that the enemy's discovered
our plan, when are we executing it?
We've moved it up. We set sail in 72 hours.
I'm told that most of the crew perished in the bombing.
There were no casualties during the bombing.
You're the hero of the Second Battle of Mars.
I'm sure you speak the truth.
This plan is being executed under UN authority,
but all the sectors are isolated from one another right now.
Unfortunately, we cannot help you directly.
Currently, it's very difficult for us, also.
Please... The entire world's hopes rest with the Yamato Plan.
Is it finally time?
The Izumo Plan entails our leaving Earth, right?
But we can't just abandon Earth.
Men.
You have all been specially trained and selected for the Izumo Plan.
Today, I will formally announce your mission.
But it is not the Izumo Plan, which was to escape the Earth.
I will explain. First, I'd like you to look at this.
This is the video message we recovered during Operation M yesterday.
I am Starsha, of the planet Iscandar.
This is...
Your planet has been almost completely destroyed by the Gamilas.
Gamilas...
I learned of this one year ago,
and dispatched my sister Yurisha to Earth
with the plans for a Dimensional Wave Motion Engine.
It's just what we saw on Mars.
If you can understand and build it,
come to Iscandar.
Our planet holds a system
which can cleanse the pollution and rebuild your planet.
What?
Unfortunately, I can no longer take it to Earth myself.
So, she's an Iscandarian.
She's pretty...
Now I have sent you the Wave Motion Core,
the activation unit for the Dimensional Wave Motion Engine, with my other sister, Sasha.
I believe that you will overcome unknown dangers and reach Iscandar.
I am Starsha, of the planet Iscandar.
One year ago, Earth received technological cooperation from Iscandar.
And we have already completed a spaceship capable of interstellar flight.
Interstellar flight...
I had no idea.
Its name is the Yamato!
Yamato?
According to the capsule,
Iscandar is 168,000 light years from Earth,
in the Large Magellanic Cloud.
This journey, of 336,000 light years, will be a voyage
like none humanity has ever experienced.
I won't force you to come. Any who wish to stay may do so.
We set sail and leave port tomorrow at 0600.
I will assume that any who do not report at that time have decided to stay behind.
That is all.
It's a shame. If only Yamamoto were still alive...
Don't say it!
I will now announce the personnel in charge of each section.
Engine room: Hikozaemon Tokugawa.
Engineering: Shiro Sanada.
Major Sanada will also serve as second-in-command.
Next is Tactics: Susumu Kodai.
Him?
Seriously?
Navigation: Daisuke Shima.
I'm coming in.
I know what you're here for.
Then that makes this easy.
You're going no matter what?
Yes.
With your body in that condition?
I'm not blind.
How many years have we known each other?
Let me go instead. That takes courage, as well.
This voyage of 168,000 light years may take my life from me.
But I will go.
I will go, and I will return!
I see. Then I've nothing else to say.
Please take care of Earth for me.
I'm told you'll also be on board the Yamato.
I requested the pilot squad, like my brother.
I'm sorry, but you'll be assigned to accounting.
You don't have to go, Dad.
You're retiring in two months!
He asked me to go. That's enough.
Aiko, say goodbye to your grandfather.
Grandpa!
Aiko... I'll be back. I'll be back, okay?
Daisuke!
Jiro! What's wrong?
Mom asked me to give you this.
She said she forgot to give it to Dad,
so she's giving it to you.
I see.
She worries too much...
Don't worry. I'll be back.
So take care of Mom until then.
Okay!
Riots in response to the Yamato Plan's announcement have worsened,
Bombing at Zone 7 Management Center Building
and rioters have destroyed the Zone 7
Management Center Building with a bomb.
The Far East Sector government is
asking rioters to remain calm, but...
I'll be back, Brother.
I'm worried...
The OMCS can make alcohol, so don't worry about that.
...for Mew!
Oh, that's it.
All inspections have been completed. All green.
guide the vehicles carrying the crew to deck 3.
Maintenance and repair teams are to begin loading the planes.
I guess this one goes to the autopilot room.
What's this?
All crew have boarded.
None are missing.
All that's left is the engine.
This is the Wave Motion Core.
So this capsule is the last part we need?
Activate
The engine output has been confirmed.
Has the engine started?
No, we need a lot of power for that to happen.
That's pretty mean of our goddess...
All crew are to change into their uniforms after reporting in.
Follow your superior's orders,
and remain on standby at your station.
Tactical Officer...
I'll obey your orders. Since you're my commanding officer.
But if I get any of the men killed for nothing,
you'll pay the price for it.
Don't worry about that.
I'm counting on you.
I'll make it home... I'll make it home for sure.
Oh, you're on this ship, too?
Yes. You're the tactical officer, Kodai, right?
I'm the operations officer, Yuki Mori. Nice to meet you.
Where's the captain?
Who is it?
Susumu Kodai.
Come in.
Excuse me.
What is it?
Yes, sir. It's about my position as tactical officer.
I...
...still don't have the right to accept it!
All of our candidates for section leaders died in yesterday's bombing.
But...
The man who was to sit in your seat was another one whom I killed.
Mamoru Kodai, your brother.
I've examined your record.
And I've decided that you are more than capable of executing your mission.
The rest,
you decide for yourself.
What's his deal? So rude.
Hey!
So this is the first bridge?
I'm Daisuke Shima, in charge of navigation. We've met before, haven't we?
The captain's above.
Oh, Kodai.
What's wrong? Did something happen?
I'm fine. There's no problem.
I'm Executive Officer Sanada. All first bridge crew is here, yes?
Yes, sir.
All crew to your stations at once!
Confirm the situation with command.
Response from command.
An interplanetary ballistic missile has been sighted heading for Earth.
Its target is...
this ship!
We can't set sail yet?
We need much more energy to launch the ship.
The problem is where we get that energy.
No way...
We'll make it in time, right?
Stay calm!
Comms, get command on the line.
Oh, Captain Okita.
How are we with the power supply?
We've begun routing all power from the Far East Sector to the Yamato.
Whether that will be enough...
All power in the Far East Sector is down!
Switch to backups.
Switching to backups.
Without power, we'll have to call off the launch.
Commander, look at this.
Yamazaki!
This is...
North America, Africa, Eurasia...
Every sector is sending the Yamato energy!
The whole world is sending power to the Yamato.
Well?
It worked. We can fire up the engine.
Activate the Wave Motion Engine!
Activating engine. Connecting flywheel.
Pressure rising... 90%... 96%... 100%...
Energy charge at 120%.
Wave Motion Engine RPMs looking good. Here we go!
Interplanetary ballistic missile spotted!
Raise the ship! Remove the camouflage!
This is...
This ship was camouflaged to deceive the enemy.
Camouflage...
Then that sunken battleship we saw...
Yes, it was the Yamato...
Space Battleship Yamato!
We will shoot down the enemy's
interplanetary ballistic missile here.
Prepare to fire main cannon!
To your positions!
Set sail! Launch the Yamato!
Set sail! Launching the Yamato!
Shock cannon has finished receiving energy charge from the engine.
Clear sight on the enemy.
Begin automatic tracking.
Automatic tracking ready.
Lock on target. Correct for errors -1.3!
Target lock.
Open fire!
Fire!
Power is coming back on line.
The Yamato...
Did it melt and burn up in the atmosphere?
The Yamato is fine!
Releasing Wave Motion Shields. No damage to the Yamato.
Kodai.
Y-Yes, sir?
Well done.
Be happy.
Episode 2
Toward a Sea of Stars
Believe
A star will shine today
Above your head
Even far away
It pours down onto us
The same brilliance
Surely it is the way to return
A small hope to light it up
To the sky you gaze upon
If I pray to eternity for a connection
Even in days of sorrow
Can we meet once again?
The heart knows it is all right
Will it be a mutual promise?
The time has come to set sail.
The Yamato heads for the planet of hope.
You... You are the only ones who can save Earth!
Cross the light barrier and fly, Yamato!
And now, the Yamato's true form is revealed.
What terrifying power does it hold?
Next time: Escaping the Mars Sphere.
There are 364 days left until humanity becomes extinct.